Cabot, Richard C. (Richard Clarke), 1868-1939. Papers of Richard Clarke Cabot: an inventory
Harvard University Archives
- Material Arranged and Described in 1997
  - Teaching material, (3 boxes); HUG 4255.40
    - Social Ethics 20A (Box Box 1)
    - Sociology 14 / Social Ethics 8 (Box Box 1)
    - Sociology 17 / Social Ethics 16 (Box Box 1)
    - Sociology 2 (Box Box 2)
    - Stenciled Cases (Box Box 2)
    - Andover Simmons (Box Box 2)
    - A-N 1934- S.-G. (Box Box 2)
    - Scrapbook: Sociology (Box Box 3)
  - Lectures of Professor Rosenstock-Huessy at 101 Brattle Street, 1938-1939, (1 box); HUG 4255.41
    Excerpts from his book Out of Revolution, pamphlets (The Multiformity of Man: Ecodynamics of a Mechanized World. A Course in the Philosophy of Modern Society, A Classic and a Founder: I. The Scientific Grammar of Michael Faraday's Diaries, and A Classic and a Founder: II. Tripartition in the Life of Theophrastus Paracelsus, correspondence, stenographic reports of Lectures I-VI, and mimeographed material used in course.
  - Medical Case Records
    - Dr. Cabot's medical records, 1896-1939, 2 folders and 36 volumes (8 boxes); HUG 4255.105
      Dr. Cabot's medical records from his practice. Includes a card index to the volumes.
      The following is a list of contents:
      - Records, 1896-1897, (1 folder) (Box Box 1)
      - June 1898-1906, (6 volumes) (Box Box 1)
      - Jan. 11, 1907-May 14, 1909, (6 volumes) (Box Box 2)
      - May 14, 1909-December 12, 1910, (5 volumes) (Box Box 3)
      - December 10, 1910-June 14, 1912, (5 volumes) (Box Box 4)
      - June 19, 1912-February 12, 1914, (4 volumes) (Box Box 5)
      - Feb. 13, 1914-September 24, 1915, (4 volumes) (Box Box 6)
      - Sept. 25, 1915-May 25, 1926, (6 volumes) (Box Box 7)
      - "Volume 37,", [ June 1926?- ]; (1 folder) (Box Box 8)
      - Card index, A-Z (Box Box 8)
    - Autopsied Cases, 1893-1914, (5 boxes); HUG 4255.106
      Contains numbered autopsied cases from Massachusetts General Hospital, autopsied cases from John Hopkins Hospital; anatomical findings in 3000 cases, 1893-1914, with analysis of findings.
      - [Cases] 1-1199 (Volume vols. 1-4, Box Box 1)
      - [Cases] 1200-2399 (Volume vols. 5-8, Box Box 2)
      - [Cases] 2400-2649 (Volume vols. 9-12, Box Box 3)
      - [Cases] 3200-3376 (Volume vol. 13, Box Box 4)
      - 10,000 Autopsies, diagnoses (Box Box 4)
      - 3,000 Autopsies, classification of all findings (Box Box 4)
      - 3,000 Autopsies, cases cause of death (Box Box 4)
      - Autopsies from Johns Hopkins Hospital (Box Box 4)
      - Autopsies Proceedings, no. 1, v. 5-8 (Box Box 4)
      - Autopsies Proceedings, no. 1, v. 9-10 (Box Box 5)
      - Autopsies Proceedings, no. 1, v. 11 (Box Box 5)
    - Case records, ante-mortem and post-mortem, 1915-1930, 16 volumes, index, 1 box of unbound records (11 boxes); HUG 4255.107
      Contains Case Records, ante-mortem and post-mortem, as used in weekly clinico-pathological exercises at the Massachusetts General Hospital, 1915-1930.
      - Volume 1 (Box Box 1)
      - Volumes 2-3 (Box Box 2)
      - Volumes 4-5 (Box Box 3)
      - Volumes 6-7 (Box Box 4)
      - Volumes 8-9 (Box Box 5)
      - Volumes 10-11 (Box Box 1)
      - volumes 12-14 (Box Box 6)
      - volume 15-16 (Box Box 7)
      - Index cards to case records (Box Boxes 8-10)
      - [Index to Case Records?] By autopsy number (Box Box 11)
      - Case Records, ante-and post-mortem, (3 folders) (Box Box 11)